1. Create a new column ‘Sales’ or ‘Order value’  [Hint: Sales = Qty*price per qty*(1- % Discount)]. Create a card visual displaying the total sales.---Done

 

2. Similarly calculate the Sales from discounted products and display the total sales from discounted products.

 

3. Since supermarkets sell bulk items, store managers want to know each order's cart value. Create a column “Cart Value” that categorizes the order value/sales as Low, medium, high or very high.                  

Cart Value,

                  < 1000: Low

                  <3500: Medium

                  < 10000: High

                   > 10000: Very High

 

                
Create a pie chart with Cart value as legend and Order value in Values field.

 

4. Separately visualize the total sales just from the low cart value category (as mentioned, any value below 1000 can be considered as low value category).

 

5. Using card visual, track the total sales coming from the low cart category and discount more than or equal to 50% to find out the contribution and cause.

[Hint: Create a new measure, sales using calculate() and sum() function with the two filters, Low cart category and discount>=50%   OR  calculate sales using sumx() with if() and and()]

 

6. Find out the number of days it takes to deliver for each shipment type (refer ship mode) so that delivery issues can be looked at on priority [Hint: No of days to deliver can be calculated from the difference between order_date and shipping_date]. Create a column chart that shows the average number of days it takes to deliver for each shipment type.

 

7. So far the store manager has managed to see the current snapshot of the sales based on various criteria. In the Retail business, do we see a spike in sales on special occasions like festivals? To achieve this, create a matrix visualization that displays order date as hierarchy , sales and sales year to date.

 

8. Visualize the cumulative sales for each month for all the years to calculate Year on Year Sales Growth. Calculate YoY growth.
